<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="cosmic_atspi_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2024 System76

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>
  <description summary="atspi accessibility protocol">
    This protocol provides a relatively straightforward mapping of AtpsiDevice
    in the at-spi2-core library, so it's possible to add a Wayland backend for it.

    This provides a way for screen reader key bindings to work.

    This is a temporary solution until a better protocol is available for this purpose.
  </description>
  <interface name="cosmic_atspi_manager_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="atspi manager global">
      Manager for adding grabs and monitoring key input.
    </description>
    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="Destroy the global">
        Any grabs that are still active will be disabled.
      </description>
    </request>
    <request name="add_key_grab">
      <description summary="Add grab for key combination">
        Grab the given key combination, so it will not be sent to clients.
      </description>
      <arg name="mods" type="uint" summary="modifiers"/>
      <arg name="virtual_mods" type="array" summary="keycodes of virtual modifiers"/>
      <arg name="key" type="uint" summary="keycode"/>
    </request>
    <request name="remove_key_grab">
      <description summary="Remove grab for key combination">
        Disables a grab added with add_key_grab.
      </description>
      <arg name="mods" type="uint" summary="modifiers"/>
      <arg name="virtual_mods" type="array" summary="keycodes of virtual modifiers"/>
      <arg name="key" type="uint" summary="keycode"/>
    </request>
    <request name="grab_keyboard">
      <description summary="Grab keyboard">
        Grab keyboard, so key input will not be sent to clients.
      </description>
    </request>
    <request name="ungrab_keyboard">
      <description summary="Ungrab keyboard">
        Disables a grab added with grab_keyboard.
      </description>
    </request>
    <event name="key_events_eis">
      <description summary="Get eis socket fd">
        Produces an fd that can be used with libei to monitor keyboard input.
      </description>
      <arg name="fd" type="fd" summary="eis file descriptor"/>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
