<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="cosmic_corner_radius_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2024 System76

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <description summary="communicate corner radius of windows">
    This protocol provides a way for clients to communicate the
    corner radius of their toplevels, should they use rounded corners.

    This hint can then be used by the compositor to draw fitting outlines
    or prevent overdrawing of other server-side drawn interfaces.
  </description>

  <interface name="cosmic_corner_radius_manager_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="corner radius global">
      Manager for creating corner-radius objects for existing toplevels
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="Destroy the global">
        Informs the server, that the client will no longer use this global.
        Any previously created corner-radius objects remain valid until destroyed.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="get_corner_radius">
      <description summary="Create a new corner-radius object for an existing toplevel">
        Instantiate an interface extension for the given xdg_toplevel to specify their corner radius.

        If the given xdg_toplevel already has a cosmic_corner_radius_toplevel_v1 object associated,
        the corner_radius_exists protocol error will be raised.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="cosmic_corner_radius_toplevel_v1"
        summary="the new cosmic_corner_radius_toplevel_v1 object"/>
      <arg name="toplevel" type="object" interface="xdg_toplevel"
        summary="the toplevel"/>
    </request>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="corner_radius_exists" value="0"
        summary="the toplevel already has a corner-radius object"/>
    </enum>
  </interface>

  <interface name="cosmic_corner_radius_toplevel_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="corner radius toplevel">
      The corner-radius object provides a way to specify a corner-radius
      for it's associated toplevel.

      If the xdg_toplevel associated with the cosmic_corner_radius_toplevel_v1
      object has been destroyed, this object becomes inert. Any further requests
      other than destroy will raise the toplevel_destroyed protocol error.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="Destroy the corner-radius object">
        Informs the server that the client will no longer be using this protocol
        object. The corner radius will be unset on the next commit.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="set_radius">
      <description summary="Set corner radius">
        This request sets the hinted corner radius values for rectangular windows.

        The corner radius hint is double-buffered state and will be applied on
        the next wl_surface.commit.

        The value is given in logical space relative to the window geometry of the
        associated xdg_toplevel. If any value exceeds a quarter of either dimension
        of the window geometry the radius_too_large protocol error is raised.
      </description>
      <arg name="top_left" type="uint" summary="top-left corner radius"/>
      <arg name="top_right" type="uint" summary="top-right corner radius"/>
      <arg name="bottom_right" type="uint" summary="bottom-right corner radius"/>
      <arg name="bottom_left" type="uint" summary="bottom-left corner radius"/>
    </request>

    <request name="unset_radius">
      <description summary="Unset corner radius">
        Unsets any previously hinted corner radius values without invalidating the object for later use.
        Can be used by clients that possibly have temporary irregular shapes.
      </description>
    </request>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="toplevel_destroyed" value="0"
        summary="the associated toplevel object has been already destroyed"/>
      <entry name="radius_too_large" value="1"
        summary="the associated toplevel's window geometry isn't large enough for the requested radius"/>
    </enum>
  </interface>
</protocol>
